ILGWU. Jay Mazur papers, 5780/203
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series I. ILGWU
  - ILGWU, Professional and Clerical Employees (PACE), 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Memo to Mazur from PACE director Ann Hoffman re PACE organizing activities at Johnny Appleseed's (Beverly, MA), The Company Store (La Crosse, WI), Milton Hershey School (Hershey, PA), Teximpor (North Bergen, NJ), Bestform (Johnstown, PA), Deb Shops (Philadelphia, PA), Bon Ton-Pomeroys (York, PA), Burlington Coat Factory Warehouse (Burlington, NJ), Charming Shoppes (Bensalem, PA), Conston Corp. (Philadelphia), Casual Male (Boston, MA), Strawbridge & Clothier (Philadelphia), March 30, 1990; meeting agenda re organizing activities, January 19, 1989; press release, "Workers Set to Rally at New York's 'Other Daily News'" re Chosun Daily News (New York's first Korean-language newspaper) abuses during organization drive, October 17, 1990; new member fact sheet, signed by Mazur, Hoffman, other union officials, May 15, 1990; memo to Mazur from Hoffman detailing Matawan-Aberdeen Board of Education (NJ) tentative agreement, February 1, 1990; letter to Mazur from Hoffman informing him of possible lawsuit by Matawan Regional Teachers Association against teachers who invited organizing by PACE, June 12, 1989; memo to Mazur from Hoffman re PACE organizing and research staff, with attached agenda for training conference, March 22, 1990; draft letter from Mazur to Barry Liebowitz, M.D., president, Doctors Council, noting desire to expand union to include white- and pink-collar workers, proposing meeting to explore affiliating, with cover memo to Mazur from Hoffman, September 15, 1989; correspondence between Mazur and AFL-CIO president Lane Kirkland re establishing an office of work and family within the federation, June-July 1989; letter to Hoffman from the Department for Professional Employees, AFL-CIO, re invitation from Histadrut to trip to Israel, March 17, 1989; PACE press release, "Study Calls for Action to Boost Child Care Workers' Wages Above Poverty Level," March 6, 1989; letter to Mazur from Hoffman re endorsement by ILGWU of March for Women's Equality/Women's Lives (April 9, 1989, Washington, D.C.) and amicus brief for Center for Constitutional Rights in Webster v. Reproductive Health Services, with attached statement by ILGWU supporting women's right to choose abortion, February 27, 1989; PACE organizing plan, August 1, 1989; confidential memo to Mazur from Hoffman re first draft of master plan for PACE, c. 1987; reply from Mazur noting no problems, June 26, 1987; correspondence re personnel matters; flyers; newspaper clipping
  - ILGWU, Professional and Clerical Employees (PACE), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Letter from Hunter College Development Office soliciting funds to establish the Paul DuBrul Fellowship, December 12, 1988, with cover note to Mazur from director of PACE Ann Hoffman; note from Hoffman re her inclusion in Who's Who of American Women, December 14, 1988; memo from Hoffman to Sal Giardina re organizing Matawan, NJ, support staff unit, with newspaper clippings, November 3; press release, "Major Campaign Set To Bolster First-Ever VDT Health Safety Law" re information hotline by PACE to assist office workers in learning about rights under the new Suffolk (Long Island, NY) law protecting users of computer monitors (video display terminals), with PACE/ILGWU Health & Safety Department brochure, "Do You Know What the VDT in Your Office Is Doing To You?" October 19; memo to Mazur from Hoffman re establishing the hot line, July 30; urgent memo from Hoffman to Mazur re imminent wildcat strike of Borg Textiles workers in Rossville, GA, (local 550), asking him to call local president, September 29; memos to Mazur from Hoffman re several hiring recommendations (organizers, field directors, interns, and temps); memo to Mazur from Hoffman urging that the union sign on to an amicus brief in the drug testing case before the Supreme Court, June 10; memo to Mazur from Hoffman asking approval for purchase of $2,816 worth of paperclips, buttons, and bumper stickers as giveaway items, with OK notation from Mazur, June 10; memo to Mazur from Hoffman urging him to sign letter to Suffolk County Executive in support of VDT legislation, June 17, 1988; memo passing on suggestion by AFL-CIO National Organizing Committee that ILGWU use actual workers in organizing campaign ads, June 6; draft AFL-CIO National Organizing Committee Proposals for Labor Law Reform Agenda, with cover memo to Mazur from Hoffman noting that it is an alternative to Donahue proposal, June 6; memo to Mazur from Hoffman expressing extreme concern about Tom Donahue's labor law reform proposal as making unions look weak, suggesting alternatives, May 24; policy paper by Institute for Women's Policy Research, "Unnecessary Losses: Costs to Americans of the Lack of Family and Medical Leave," with press release, "Lack of Parental Leave Costs $715 Million Annually," with cover letter to Mazur from Hoffman, April 7; agenda on conference by the AFL-CIO Department for Professional Employees on organizing professional, technical, and salaried women, with memo from Hoffman, April 5; memo to Mazur that PACE has opened an office in Barre, Vermont, to facilitate organizing at National Life, February 17; PACE Report to the General Executive Board, February 1988; memo from Hoffman to ILGWU regional directors discussing relationship of PACE to ILGWU, October 23, 1987; handwritten note to Mazur from Hoffman that union obtained ratified agreement covering K Mart Dallas distribution center, February 24, 1988; memo to Mazur from Hoffman that contracts were obtained for three elusive companies, January 7; letter of invitation to Hoffman from People to People International, inviting her to join a delegation to China, with cover memo to Mazur noting that she declined, January 22; booklet re ILGWU benefits; newspaper clippings
  - ILGWU, Professional and Clerical Employees (PACE), 1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Memos to Mazur from Hoffman re several hiring recommendations; memo to Mazur from Hoffman re losing another organizer for financial reasons, to ACTWU, November 25; memos re clerical organizing efforts targeting insurance industry by Connecticut State AFL-CIO, with OPEIU, SEIU, and AFSCME participating, suggesting PACE/ILGWU also participate, with OK notation by Mazur, November 17; memo re potential organizing interest by clericals at Cornell ILR extension center in New York, with notation by Mazur to proceed, November 16; memo to Mazur from Hoffman suggesting adding scholarships for members' child care and adult dependent care expenses, possible foundation support, November 5; letters from Hoffman to NJ Gov. Kean and to chair of Task Force on Equitable Compensation urging support of pay equity legislation, October 29; memo to Mazur from Hoffman re future advertising plans for ILGWU, need for market research before embarking on ad campaigns, noting last one sent wrong message, October 15; PACE Report to General Executive Board, noting reactivation in June 1987 after being dormant since its creation in 1984, discusses organizing activity, October 1987; voucher for $1000 plus correspondence re contribution to National Institute for Women of Color as agent for Institute for Women's Policy research for study of wages of child care workers, September 21; galley proof of Executive Council Report on Working Women, with editing suggestions from Hoffman, September 9; letter to Mazur from Hoffman asking for approval of her joining the board of New Jersey Citizen Action, with OK by Mazur, September 1; letter asking permission to attend Graves, W.VA., union organizer retreat, August 27; memo to Mazur from Hoffman re newly created Institute for American Values, and organization with "an admittedly horrible but useful name," designed to take away the issue of the family from the Right in a productive way, with attached prospectus for developing a national family agenda supporting child care, pro-family workplace, pay equity, stronger child support enforcement, with newspaper clippings, August 20; memo from Hoffman to ILGWU Midwest Region director Lou Montenegro re possible meeting with Spiegel re catalog sales and telemarketing, organizing Hispanic workers and Midwest region generally, August 7; memo to Mazur from Hoffman suggesting greater use of members of Graphic Artists Guild for graphic needs, with attached letter from AFL-CIO Department for Professional Employees, which notes efforts to persuade Guild to affiliate, August 7; memo to Mazur from Hoffman listing her "outside" board memberships, asking for approval to continue, with OK from Mazur, July 20; memo to Mazur from Hoffman re proposed supplemental agreement for 1988 negotiations giving union the right to represent office workers based on a card majority, November 5; letter to NY Gov. Mario Cuomo from Hoffman, with separate explanatory note to Mazur, opposing state's proposed pay-equity plan for state workers, July 8, and letter to Hoffman from Public Employees Federation president Rand Condell thanking her, August 4; PACE Advisory Committee meeting agenda, July 27, with cover FYI memo to Mazur; memo from Mazur to ILGWU officials and regional directors re reactivation of PACE to become a major player in the organization of white collar workers, appointment of Ann Hoffman as director, June 26 and 24; memo to Mazur from ILGWU general secretary-treasurer Irwin Solomon noting that PACE will be treated as separate department, July 20; letter to Mazur from AFL-CIO Department of Professional Employees informing him that affiliation has been accepted, May 13; outline of strategy for organizing white collar workers, n.d., possibly presented as speech by Mazur at meeting; meeting agenda, n.d.
  - ILGWU, Professional and Clerical Employees (PACE), 1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Memo re union representation election results at New Horizons for the Retarded, Inc., in Ellenville, NY, February 11, 1986; related materials
  - ILGWU, Benefit Funds, 1984-1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    see also Benefit Funds – Financial Responsibilities 1994; see also ILGWU Health Services 1981-1987 Retirement Fund plan amendments, Dec. 4, 1988; transcript of ABC Evening News broadcast of Dec. 29, 1986, re union pension plan fraud; letter from dental plan provider, Feb. 27. 1987; memos re well baby coverage, memo from ILGWU VP Susan Cowell re importance of liberal maternity/paternity leave policies, Dec. 2, 1986; policy manual covering medical, life insurance, retirement, and other benefits, April 1986; letter to NYS legislative staff supporting mail-order pharmacy services, May 23, 1986; agenda for Workers' Benefits Committee, June 13, 1984; list of retirees with medical coverage, April 16, 1997; schedule of sick benefit increases, June 14, 1988; Forbes article with cover note to Mazur, Dec. 12, 1988; balance of accounts in Upper South Department Health & Welfare Fund, 1986
  - ILGWU, Benefit Retirement Fund, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Draft report, "Union Retirees: Enriching Their Lives, Enhancing Their Contribution," by National Institute for Work and Learning, May 1998; Director's Report to the Retirement Committee of the ILGWU Retirement Fund, December 6, 1988; letter re investment policy for staff retirement fund, September 17, 1987; letters from Retired Officers of the ILGWU re health insurance premiums, February 19 and October 15, 1986, with reply from Mazur; notification of settlement of claim re Petro-Lewis Securities Litigation, copy of check, October 20
  - ILGWU, Death Benefit Fund, Investment Performance Review, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Towers Perrin performance report on first quarter 1995
  - ILGWU, Staff Benefit Fund, Investment Performance Review, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - ILGWU, National Retirement Fund-Arnold and Porter, 1977-1994 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Financial statements; letter to Mazur from Arnold & Porter re demand for change in contribution assessment by employer group in current collective bargaining negotiations, May 27, 1994; letter to Mazur re fund contribution negotiations with Rain or Shine and Jainard, July 25, 1990
  - UNITE Retiree Health Benefits, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - ILGWU, Benefits, National Retirement Fund, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Report of the Director to the Board of Trustees, ILGWU National Retirement Fund, December 11, 1990; agenda of December 11, 1990, meeting; Investment Report, ILGWU – National Retirement Fund through September 30, 1990, by Pacific Investment Management Company; ILGWU National Retirement Fund Actuarial Valuation and Review as of January 1, 1990, by Martin E. Segal Company; printout, ILGWU Staff Retirement Fund Retirees Birthdate Sequence, May 30, 1990; minutes of joint meeting, Executive Committee and Finance Committee, August 29, 1990; minutes of Finance Committee meetings, January 24, March 21, and June 19, 1990; minutes of Executive Committee meeting, May 15, 1990; minutes of Executive Committee meeting and of Board of Trustees meetings, December 13, 1989; minutes of the Finance Committees of the Death Benefit Fund and Staff Retirement Fund, August 29, 1990; minutes of General Fund Pooled Investment Committee meeting, August 30, 1990; meeting agendas; correspondence from Buck Consultants re Death Benefit Fund, Staff Retirement Fund, and General Fund performance, third quarter, November 12, 1990; correspondence from Towers Perrin recommending replacing Wertheim Asset Management Services as the fund's fixed asset manager, April 1989; report by Towers Perrin, "Analysis of Fixed Income Managers Sanford C. Bernstein & Company and Pacific Investment Management Company"; letter to Mazur from Wertheim Asset Management Services expressing regret at decision to replace them, May 23, 1989; handwritten notes by Mazur
  - ILGWU, Benefits, National Retirement Fund, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Investment Report and Accounting Report, ILGWU – National Retirement Fund through September 30, 1989, by Pacific Investment Management Company; ILGWU National Retirement Fund Actuarial Valuation and Review as of January 1, 1989, by Martin E. Segal Company; ILGWU National Retirement Fund Report of Withdrawal Liability as of December 31, 1989, by Martin E. Segal Company; summary of fund management companies with annual rates of return, prepared by Buck Consultants, March 26, 1986; total of all funds, asset breakdown as of June 30, 1989, with rates of return for all funds; printout, ILGWU Staff Retirement Fund Retirees Benefit Sequence, May 29, 1990; meeting agendas; minutes of joint meeting of Executive/Finance Committees, April 11, 1989; minutes of Finance Committee, May 16 and October 6, 1989; minutes of Executive Committee, December 12, 1988; minutes of Board of Trustees, December 6 and 12, 1988; proposed amendments; memo to Mazur from director of the National Retirement Fund requesting approval of a temporary, part-time return to work by a recently retired clerk in the Nassau-Suffolk District office, August 9, 1989; Southern District court opinion and order re Anita Foundations and pension plan withdrawal liability of 12 defunct apparel companies, April 1989; correspondence with attorneys re conflict of interest of a trustee representing a withdrawn firm, August-December 1989; memo re reallocation of funds from equities to fixed-income to rebalance portfolio, April 25, 1990; routine correspondence
  - ILGWU, National Retirement Fund, 1977-1980 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Financial statements
  - ILGWU, National Retirement Fund, Western Asset Management Company, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Memos to Mazur re bankruptcy of Bank of New England, impact on bond holdings for the National Retirement Fund, February 1 and April 15, 1991
  - ILGWU, National Retirement Fund, Executive Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Annual Meeting proposed agendas for Executive Committee and Board of Trustees, December 12, 1988; Report of the Director to the Board of Trustees, ILGWU National Retirement Funds, December 12, 1988; Pension Plan Rules and Regulations as Amended through December 16, 1987; Finance Committee minutes; Report of Withdrawal Liability as of December 31, 1987; Actuarial Valuation and Review as of January 1, 1988; accountants statements; revised and additional plan amendments, December 7, 1988; agenda of December 1991 meeting; status of withdrawal liability as of December 31, 1990; memo re withdrawal liability, September 30, 1991; spreadsheet of statement of assets available for benefits, December 31, 1990; handwritten notes
  - ILGWU, National Retirement Fund, 1982-1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Minutes of Executive Committee and Finance Committee meetings, summary plan descriptions
  - ILGWU, National Retirement Fund, reports, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Reports on withdrawal liability; valuation and review; report of the director to the Board of Trustees; description of Amivest Capital Management; Executive Committee meeting agenda, November 12, 1985
- Series II. Subject files
  - A. Philip Randolph Institute (APRI), 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Budget summary and details, 1990, with cover memo to officers from administrative director re financial crisis, noting that APRI finances were never based on a proper budgeting formula; letter to Mazur from APRI president Norman Hill asking fro assistance in obtaining contributions; letter to Mazur inviting ILGWU to send a prominent black female representative to APRI 20th national conference for tribute dinner to black trade union women, with reply from Mazur identifying vice president Mattie Jackson, April 13, 1989; letter from APRI urging boycott of Harvey Industries in Athens, TX, over striking Local 376 of the Furniture Workers Division of the International Union of Electronic, Electrical, Salaried, Machine and Furniture Workers, February 22, 1989; letter to Mazur from Hill asking him to write to Chemical Bank of New York asking that it cease making loans to South African Minorco, with attached fact sheet, February 6, 1989
  - A. Philip Randolph Institute (APRI), 1983-1988 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Letter to Mazur informing him of his election to the National Board of the A. Philip Randolph Institute, Feb. 3, 1987; Annual Report 1986; conference program, "Turning Back the Tide: Blacks and Labor in the 1984 Elections," annual conference of APRI, May 11-13, 1984; report of the eighteenth national conference, May 7-10, 1987; speech by Mazur, May 8, 1987; memo reporting second part of conference, with list of ILGWU delegates; reminder to Mazur from APRI president re list of contributions by ILGWU locals, May 25, 1984; draft of APRI pamphlet re the changing condition of workers, black workers, and the black-labor alliance, soliciting comments by Mazur, August 19, 1987; proposal for Africa Watch, to monitor human rights abuses by black African governments, February 29, 1988; article by ILGWU assist. Pres. Gus Tyler about A. Philip Randolph, n.d.
  - A. Philip Randolph Institute (APRI) Conference, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Text of speech by Mazur, April 13, 1987; conference announcement for "Work in '87: Win in '88," eighteenth national conference at San Francisco Hilton, A. Philip Randolph Institute
  - AT&T, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Letter to Mazur from AT&T re new administrative software developed in cooperation with the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) and installed and maintained by the Communication Workers of America (CWA), May 20, 1987; letter to New York Telephone Company about a billing error, March 23, 1988
  - Abeles Schwartz Associates, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    See also NYC Garment District; see also New York City – 42nd St. Redevelopment Project 1984 Letters from planning and development consultants re NYC's industrial retention program; activity reports for October and November 1983 re Chinatown Garment Industry; ideas for discussion with Carol Ballamy re GIDC, Chinatown
  - Abrams, Robert, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    ILGWU campaign literature for Robert Abrams for U.S. Senator, in English, Spanish, and Chinese, with list of polling places and cover letter to Mazur, April 9, 1992; handwritten letter to Mazur from union member thanking him for guidance in voting, with attached letter sent to members from Mazur endorsing Abrams and local candidates, September 17, 1992; letters from Mazur to presidents of several other unions asking them to sign a letter endorsing Abrams, with faxed reply from Communication Workers of America president Morton Bahr suggesting a change, July 1, 1991; letter signed by presidents of several unions endorsing Abrams; proposed field organization for senor citizen vote, June 23, 1992; letters from Abrams to Mazur thanking him for his support, June 1991-September 1992; two drafts of Abrams speech to be delivered before the AFL-CIO Committee on Political Education (COPE), written by Gus Tyler, with cover note from Tyler to Mazur, February 4 and 5, 1991; letter from Robert Abrams asking for early support, June 24, 1991; report of statewide poll for Senate race conducted by COPE, July 8-14, 1991; copy of State of New York 1989 Election Law; memo to Mazur from political consultant Ethan Geto summarizing strategy discussed at meeting, need to form ad hoc labor committee for Abrams, encourage public endorsement by Carol Bellamy to discourage run by Geraldine Ferraro and Elizabeth Holtzman, February 1, 1991; list of labor leaders supporting Abrams, with handwritten additions by Mazur; letter from Abrams to Mazur thanking him for support in re-election as Attorney General, December 11, 1990
  - Africa, 1986-1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    See also South Africa; see also Nigeria; see also Zimbabwe Letter to Mazur from executive director of A. Philip Randolph Educational Fund with draft outline and proposed budget for establishment of Africa Watch to monitor the human rights situation in targeted African countries, February 29, 1988; letter confirming scheduled meeting between Mazur and Jean Michael Bokambo Yangouma, general secretary of the Congolese Labor Confederation, first vice president of the Superior Council of the Republic, and favorite to win election as prime minister or president, January 9, 1992; Ditchley Foundation conference outline and subsequent report, "Africa: Problems and Prospects. What Is Required in Terms of Political Management, Development Policies and Relief Aid?" January 26-28, 1990; draft code of conduct for investment in South Africa in a post-apartheid non-sanction environment, with cover letter to ILGWU Director of International Affairs Michele Briones from the deputy executive director of the AFL-CIO African-American Labor Center, July 17, 1992; handwritten notes re men's/boy's and women's/girl's clothing manufacturers in South Africa, and number employed, n.d.; note from Mazur to deputy executive director of the African-American Labor Center assenting to extension of stay of Fisseha Tekie in Ethiopia, June 3, 1992; memo from African-American Labor Center noting that Sayed Mohamed Rashid, president of the General Trade Union for Textiles, had been elected president of the Egyptian Trade Union Federation, May 7, 1992; letter to Michele Briones from national general secretary of free trade unions of Burkina Faso (Organisation Nationale des Syndicats Libres), thanking her and ILGWU for support of African trade unionists (English translation and French original), November 30, 1994; memo to Mazur from Briones re Norman Lewis's trip to Africa, October 27, 1986
  - Agreements, Greater Blouse, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 13)